irisopenspace.co.uk 2013-06-17

# IRIS OpenSpace

## IRIS Software Group is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy sets out how we will use and protect personal information that you give us when you use our websites at [www.irisopenspace.co.uk](http://www.irisopenspace.co.uk/) ("our Websites"). 

If you have any questions or comments about this policy please write to Data Controller, IRIS Software Group Limited, Riding Court House, Riding Court Road, Datchet SL3 9JT. If you have any questions about the security at our website, please contact us at [webmaster@iris.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@iris.co.uk). 

## Acceptance

By accessing and using our Websites, you signify your agreement to this policy. If you do not agree with the policy, please do not use our Websites. This policy is subject to change. Any changes we may make to this policy in the future will be posted on this page and your continued use of our Websites following the posting of changes will mean you accept those changes. 

## Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you: 

· Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Websites. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our Websites, subscribing to our services including, where applicable, newswires, booking training courses, posting material, referring friends, or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by us and when you report a problem with our Websites. 

· If you contact us through our Websites, whether by sending messages to our email addresses, filling in any forms, using any online chat service or otherwise, we may keep a record of that correspondence. 

· We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them. 

· Details of transactions you carry out through our Websites and of the fulfilment of your orders. We do not, and do not intend to, to store credit or debit card details, although our third party card payment processing providers may do so in order to process and keep a record of your payments to us and may also use card authorisation and fraud screening services to prevent against fraud. They may also pass information to fraud prevention and law enforcement agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering. 

· Details of your visits to our Websites including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access. 

## Third party websites

Our Websites may contain links that make it easy for you to visit the websites of our partner networks, advertisers, affiliates and suppliers of goods and services. If you use the links to visit any website operated by a third party, please check the privacy policy of that third party and satisfy yourself that the terms are acceptable to you before you use or submit any personal data to such website. We do not have any control over such third party websites. Information you provide or which may be collected by such website is controlled by the relevant third party provider of such website. Accordingly, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide or which may be collected by the third party provider while visiting or using such websites. 

## Accessing and updating personal information

If any of your personal information changes or becomes out of date please amend your registration details on the site or let us know by emailing us at [webmaster@iris.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@iris.co.uk). You may inform us at any time should you wish us to delete personal information we hold about you by writing to Company Secretary, IRIS Software Group Limited, Riding Court House, Riding Court Road, Datchet SL3 9JT. 

You have a right to access the personal data held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please write to Data Controller, IRIS Software Group Limited, Riding Court House, Riding Court Road, Datchet SL3 9JT. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. 

## IP addresses and cookies

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual. 

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our Websites and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us: 

· To estimate our audience size and usage pattern. 

· To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our Websites according to your individual interests. 

  * To speed up your searches. 

· To recognise you when you return to our Websites. 

We may also use cookies to collect data about your use of our Websites, to remember choices you make, to provide more enhanced personal features and to assist you to navigate certain areas of our Website. If you wish to use social sharing features in relation to items on our Websites, you may also need to consent to the use of certain third party cookies required by the relevant social networking websites. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Websites. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our Websites. 

Please note that our advertisers or other third parties who publish information on our Websites may also use cookies, over which we have no control. 

To learn more about the cookies we use and to manage your choices in relation to their use, please see our Cookies Policy here. 

## Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff, operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. 

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Websites; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

## Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways: 

· To ensure that content from our Websites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 

· To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 

· To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us. 

· To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so. 

· To allow you to participate in our competitions and promotions, when you choose to do so. 

· To notify you about changes to our service. 

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you. 

If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. 

## Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by writing to Data Controller, IRIS Software Group Limited, Riding Court House, Riding Court Road, Datchet SL3 9JT. 

## Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 2006. 

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. 

In the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party purchaser, the personal data of our customers will be one of the transferred assets. 

We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect our rights, property, or safety (or that of our customers and others). This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

## Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email.
